A Guide to the Melvin E. Steadman collection, 1698-1927
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Melvin E. Steadman collection, 1698-1927
The Library of Virginia
34683
8.7 cu. ft. (19 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
For preservation purposes, please serve microfilm (Misc. reels 1224-1246).
Acquisition Information
Purchased, May 1990.
Biographical Information
Melvin Steadman (1932-1987) was a United Methodist minister, an amateur genealogist, and a historian of Northern Virginia. These papers from his personal collection are largely from the Northern Virginia counties in which Steadman centered his own work.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1698-1927, collected by Melvin Steadman of Northern Virginia. The collection is organized into three series: Local records, Organizational records, and Private papers. Included are accounts, bonds, correspondence, court records, deeds, estate papers, financial records, plats and surveys, school records, and wills. The bulk of the collection relates to Fairfax and Loudoun Counties and includes numerous 18th century documents. The Local records comprise the largest series and include Chancery Records, Circuit Court Records, Deeds, Fiduciary Records, Free Negro and Slave Records, Indentures, Overseers of the Poor, Road and Bridge Records, School Records, and Wills.
The Organizational records include receipts and accounts of Alexandria Boarding School and Leesburg Academy, as well as records relating to the Methodist Episcopal Church in Alexandria, Falls Church, Fairfax, Lovettsville, Loudoun, and Sussex County.
The Private papers contain estate accounts and inventories for the Binns, Chichester, Cooke, Davis, Ellzey, Hamilton, Hopkins, Lane, Lewis, McCabe, Mason, Oxley, Price, Scott, Sinclair, Taylor, Updike, Whaley, and Wrenn families, among others.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Local records
Series II: Organizational records
Series III: Private papers
Contents List
- Series I: Local records, 1755-1927., Extent: 10 boxes. (Box 1-10)
  This series includes accounts, agreements, bills, bonds, court records, deeds, election records, manumissions, petitions, plats and surveys, power of attorneys, receipts, reports, road records, and wills. The counties covered include: Alexandria, Arlington, Augusta, Clarke, Culpeper, Fairfax, Fauquier, Frederick, King and Queen, King George, Loudoun, Madison, Northumberland, Pittsylvania, Prince George, Prince William, Rockingham, Stafford, and Westmoreland Counties, Virginia. Also includes information from Henderson County, Kentucky; Frederick County, Maryland; and Jefferson County, West Virginia. The collection includes many 18th century records and is a great resource for genealogists and historians.
  The materials were maintained in their original order and are arranged by category. Categories include Bonds, Circuit Court, County Court, Court of Chancery, Superior Court of Law and Chancery, Deeds, Electors Records, Fiduciary Records, Free Negro and Slave Records, Judgments, Justice of the Peace, Land Records, Marriage Records, Overseers of the Poor Records, Plats and Surveys, Reconstruction, Road and Bridge Records, School Records, and Wills.
  Of note are the numerous deeds, especially those from the 18th century. The Deeds are organized by the Deed Book in which they were recorded and many include information on the sale of land and slaves. The County Records include information relating to cases brought before the County Courts. Some of the cases include judgments, promissory notes, summons, receipts, agreements, depositions, and correspondence.
  Arranged alphabetically by county name and then by record type.
  - Alexandria County Bonds, 1788. (Box 1, Folder 1, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Bond between John Albrittain, Ignatious Byrns, Nicholas Byrne, and John Wren.
  - Alexandria County Circuit Court, 1795-1801. (Box 1, Folder 2, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    William Hepburn vs. Thomas Williams.
  - Alexandria County Deeds, 1890-1898. (Box 1, Folder 3, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between Isaac Crossman and Eleanor M. Koon (1890).
    Deed between M. E. Church, Administrator of the estate of Eleanor M. Koon, and Nannie M. Koon (1898).
  - Alexandria County Deed Book K. (Box 1, Folder 4, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    (empty)
  - Alexandria County Fiduciary Records, 1798. (Box 1, Folder 5, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Power of attorney of Richard Bannatine.
  - Alexandria County Flour Inspector Records, 1844. (Box 1, Folder 6, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Receipt for R. Crupper and Son.
  - Alexandria County Plats and Surveys, 1897. (Box 1, Folder 7, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Survey report for George O. Wunder.
  - Alexandria County Wills, 1846-1853. (Box 1, Folder 8, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Copy of and opinions regarding the will of John C. Varnell.
  - Arlington County Deed Book, 1922-1923. (Box 1, Folder 9, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between town of Falls Church and Halls Hill.
    Deed between Gordon Gott, Guy N. Church, and Merton E. Church.
  - Arlington County Deed Book 193, 1923. (Box 1, Folder 10, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between Edward Eaton, Merton E. Church, and Kenneth W. Gott.
  - Arlington County Deed Book 234, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 11, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between Edward Eaton, Merton E. Church, and Falls Church Lumber Company.
  - Arlington County Deed Book 274, 1923-1927. (Box 1, Folder 12, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between Kenneth Gott and Edward Eaton.
    Deed between Edward Eaton and Charles Seaton.
    Deed between Charles Seaton, Merton E. Church, and Falls Church Lumber Company.
  - Augusta County Unrecorded deeds, 1869. (Box 1, Folder 13, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Agreement between guardians of William Boyd and Samuel Gochenour.
  - Clarke County Bonds, 1843. (Box 1, Folder 14, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Bond between William R. Seevers, etc., and Sheriff Edward J. Smith.
  - Clarke County Marriage Records, 1836. (Box 1, Folder 15, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Marriage authorization given by Elizabeth Athens to allow her daughter Jane Jenkins to marry Thomas Davis.
  - Culpeper County Circuit Court, 1858. (Box 1, Folder 16, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    A. D. and Elizabeth Pollock vs. Glapells Administrator.
  - Culpeper County Deeds, 1793. (Box 1, Folder 17, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Partial deed of George Walters and James Duncan for land.
  - Culpeper County Deed Book FF, 1813. (Box 1, Folder 18, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between George Walters and William Beans.
  - Culpeper County Plats, 1812. (Box 1, Folder 19, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Surveys for Lawrence Broadly and Cailem Price.
  - Fairfax County Agreements, 1807. (Box 1, Folder 20, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Agreement for the sale of a slave named Tom, between Gabriel Childs and Nicholas Darne.
  - Fairfax County Bonds, 1744-1891. (Box 1, Folder 21, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    William Harris to Richard Brown (1744).
    William Layton to William Ramsay (1753).
    John Radcliff and Joseph Shreve to Thomas Coombs (1755).
    John and Sampson Trammell et. al. to inventory John Trammell estate (1755).
    William Landrum to William Black (1756).
    Thomas Williams to Samuel Talbut (1757).
    Henry Graham to Charles Carroll (1760).
    Daniel Madinger to Henry Ellison (1764)
    William Trammell to Charles Broadwater, Administrator of estate of Benjamin Sebastian (1774).
    William Bind to George Minor (1782).
    Rachel Brooke and James Keith to David Stuart, Benjamin Dulany, Richard Conway, and Roger West (1789).
    Charles Broadwater to William Gardner (1803).
    Hugh Stuart to William Lane Sr (1804).
    Charles Love and Charles Tyler Jr. to William Lane Sr. for the hire of slave, Whitley (1805).
    Joseph Lay to Richard Coleman (1805).
    Charles Love and Hall Scott to William Lane (1807).
    Thomas ap Catesby Jones to Henry S. Jones (1845).
    A. B. Darne and James B. Hunter to J. Cornell (1848).
    Asbury R. Jacobs et. al as constable (1891).
  - Fairfax County County Court, 1755-1866. (Box 1, Folder 22, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Ninian Beall vs. Thomas Fletcher (1755).
    Alexander vs. Binns (partial) (1787).
    John Bell vs. John Jenkins (1805).
    Hugh Stuart (1812).
    William Walker vs. Rubin Rouzie (1833).
    W. H. Deming vs. G. M. Hunter (1845).
    John B. Farr vs. Barrack Chick (1845).
    John Powell vs. Henry Fairfax (1847).
    Balls Administrator vs. F. D. Richardson and Elizabeth Cook (1853).
    Perman vs. G. W. Pettit (1854).
    Alexandria and Fredericksburg Railroad Co. vs. E.H. Gibbs (186).
  - Fairfax County District Court, 1788. (Box 1, Folder 23, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Robert Luttrell vs. Hugh Stuart.
  - Fairfax County Superior Court of Law and Chancery, 1811-1813. (Box 1, Folder 24, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    John A. Binns receipts.
  - Fairfax County Circuit Superior Court of Law and Chancery, 1849. (Box 1, Folder 25, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Bill in equity of John M. Jones et. al. vs. Reese Bradley and others.
  - Fairfax County Circuit Court, 1861-1897. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Thomas R. Love vs. the Great Falls Manufacturing Co.
    George A. Gordon, Administrator of Elizabeth G. Francis vs. Bailey and others.
  - Fairfax County Deeds (copies), 1793-1900. (Box 1, Folder 27, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between Henry Lee, Bryan Fairfax, and William Wilson and John Potts.
    Deed between Charles B. Purvis, Executor of Frederick G. Barbadoes, and H. H. Lowe.
  - Fairfax County Recorded Deeds, 1810. (Box 1, Folder 28, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between William Payne and George and Robert Darne.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book A, 1744. (Box 1, Folder 29, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Lease between John Parker and John Minor.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book A#4, 1859. (Box 1, Folder 30, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between Albert Willcoxan and B. F. Bittinger.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book C#5, 1882-1883. (Box 1, Folder 31, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between Jesse M. Gibson and George F. M. Walters.
    Deed between Edward Daniels and Mt. Vernon School district.
    Deed between Thomas R. Love and Berkley Kidwell.
    Deed between William Blank and Providence School district.
    Deed between John Ashford and John Davis.
    Deed between Sarah Hunter and James Horseman and Jonathan Magarety.
    Deed between Richard St. Gunnell and Fanny A. Campbell and Gertrude W. Coleman.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book C#6, 1898. (Box 1, Folder 32, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between Albert F. Fox, Amanda F. Turner, and Methodist Episcopal Church.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book D, 1755. (Box 1, Folder 33, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between Edward Harden and Samuel Russell.
    Deed between John Dalton and William Ramsay, executors for John Minor, and Charles Benson (2 copies).
  - Fairfax County Deed Book D#6, 1899. (Box 1, Folder 34, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between Jacob C. DePutron and Columbia Baptist Church of Falls Church.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book E#4, 1864-1865. (Box 1, Folder 35, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between B. F. Bittinger and E.C. Bittinger.
    Deed between Albert Orcutti and Mary E. Mills.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book E#5, 1884-1885. (Box 1, Folder 36, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between John L. Manning and the Mount Vernon School District.
    Deed between Joshua Kirby and Providence School District.
    Deed between Mason Shipman and Providence School District.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book F, 1764. (Box 1, Folder 37, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between William Wright and Thomas Asbury.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book F#4, 1863-1865. (Box 1, Folder 38, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Commissioners report on Catharine Reid dowry.
    Deed between A. H. Darne and Lester Lloyd.
    Deed between A. D. Pollock and Mary E. Mills.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book F#5, 1887. (Box 1, Folder 39, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between Isaac Crussman and Albert F. Fox.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book G, 1766. (Box 1, Folder 40, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between John Trammell and William Trammell (2 copies).
  - Fairfax County Deed Book G#4, 1860-1866. (Box 1, Folder 41, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between George B. Ives and A. E. Lounsberry, and R. G. Walrad.
    Deed between George W. West and Elizabeth Porter.
    Deed between Walter S. Ancmoody and A. E. Lounsberry.
    Deed between Richard Johnson and Walker R. Millan.
    Report on the division of the real estate of Eli Hutchison.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book H#4, 1871. (Box 1, Folder 42, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between John B. Wrenn and Martha E. Wrenn.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book I#5, 1890. (Box 1, Folder 43, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Deed between Isaac Crossman and Eleanor M. Koon.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book J#2, 1889. (Box 1, Folder 44, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1224)
    Survey for the heirs of John Reid and Martha A. Ayre.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book L, 1805. (Box 2, Folder 1, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Bill of sale between Joseph Lay and Richard Coleman.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book L#2, 1830-1837. (Box 2, Folder 2, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between William Darrell and James M. Roberdeau.
    Deed between George Jacobs and William Nelson.
    Deed between George W. Hunter and John Moss.
    Deed between William Ashford and John Bell.
    Deed between Samuel Ratcliffe and Richard Ratcliffe.
    Deed between George Chichester and John Moore.
    Deed between Charles Ratcliffe and Richard Ratcliffe.
    Deed between John Gantt and William Gantt.
    Deed between Thompson Kitchen and Elizabeth Kitchen.
    Survey and report of Margaret Fox dower.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book L#5, 1895. (Box 2, Folder 3, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between Frederick Barbadoes and John D. Avil.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book N#4, 1871. (Box 2, Folder 4, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between Joseph E. Birch and W. H. Daniel and J. G. Brunner.
    Deed between Francis D. Smith and John H. Cole.
    Deed between Alexandria and Fredericksburg Railway Company and Alexandria Water Company.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book O#3, 1849. (Box 2, Folder 5, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between Asa Rogers and Artemisian Scott.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book P#3, 1844. (Box 2, Folder 6, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between Newton Keene, Harday Bridges, and Jonathan Beard.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book Q#3, 1851. (Box 2, Folder 7, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between Thomas R. Love, Henry M. Thomas, and James Wren.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book Q#5, 1894. (Box 2, Folder 8, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between Merton E. Church, F. W. Richardson, and John D. Avil.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book T#4, 1876. (Box 2, Folder 9, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between Isaac Crossman and Methodist Episcopal Church of Falls Church.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book U#2, 1823. (Box 2, Folder 10, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between Charles Turley and George Turley.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book V#4 and V#5, 1877-1896. (Box 2, Folder 11, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed and partition of the land of John J. T. Jackson (1877).
    Deed between Robert E. Lee Jr. and R. W. Moore (1896).
  - Fairfax County Deed Book W#2, 1826. (Box 2, Folder 12, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between James M. Roberdeau and Hugh Mitchell.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book X#2, 1827. (Box 2, Folder 13, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between Constant Scott and Robert F. Scott.
  - Fairfax County Deed Books X#5 and X#6, 1891-1907. (Box 2, Folder 14, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between Brook Johnson and Oakland Hill Baptist Church (1891).
    Deed between Merton E. Church, Lyman Ballard, and Columbia Baptist Church of Falls Church (1907).
  - Fairfax County Deed Book Y#4, 1873. (Box 2, Folder 15, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Estate of James Davis and James W. A. Davis.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book Z#5, 1897. (Box 2, Folder 16, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between Merton E. Church, John D. Advil, and Frederick G. Barbadoes.
  - Fairfax County Deed Book 22, 1853. (Box 2, Folder 17, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between Daniel Kincheloe and George H. Cockerill.
  - Fairfax County Unrecorded Deeds Grantor A, 1785-1802. (Box 2, Folder 18, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between William Alexander, William Gibbons Stuart, and William Hunter (1785).
    Deed between Richard Arell and James Douglas (1802).
    Deed between George Adams and Henry Whaley (1814).
  - Fairfax County Unrecorded Deeds Grantor B, 1783-1812. (Box 2, Folder 19, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between Samuel Bayley and Michael Ryan (1783).
    Deed between Ann Bayley and Samuel Bayley (1784) (2 copies).
    Deed between Samuel Bayley and Susanna Beck (1812).
  - Fairfax County Unrecorded Deeds Grantor C, 1786. (Box 2, Folder 20, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between Gerrard Trammell and Samuel Trammell.
  - Fairfax County Unrecorded Deeds Grantor D, 1806-1831. (Box 2, Folder 21, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between William Darne and George Minor (1806).
    Deed between Benjamin R. Davis and William C. Newton (1820).
    Deed between George Darne and Robert Darne (1830).
  - Fairfax County Unrecorded Deeds Grantor E, 1815. (Box 2, Folder 22, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between H. Ellzey to John Beech.
  - Fairfax County Unrecorded Deeds Grantor H, 1833. (Box 2, Folder 23, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between George W. Hunter, trustee for George Lee Turberville, and W. Wrenn.
  - Fairfax County Unrecorded Deeds Grantor L, 1818. (Box 2, Folder 24, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between Margaret Lay and Henry McKenzie.
  - Fairfax County Unrecorded Deeds Grantor N, 1800. (Box 2, Folder 25, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between George Newman and John Alexander.
  - Fairfax County Unrecorded Deeds Grantor T, 1830. (Box 2, Folder 26, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between George L. Turberville and Alexander Turley (1830).
  - Fairfax County Unrecorded Deeds Grantor W, 1757-1797. (Box 2, Folder 27, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between Joseph West and John Queen (1757).
    Deed between Roger West and Thomas Ludwell Lee (1797)
  - Fairfax County Fiduciary Records, 1804-1849. (Box 2, Folder 28, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Power of attorney of Sampson Darrell (1804).
    Power of attorney of Mary Darrell (1820).
    Power of attorney of J. Clement Darrell (1820).
    Power of attorney of Joshua Jordon (1823).
    Power of attorney of Amelia Trammell Darne (1849).
  - Fairfax County Free Negro and Slave Records, Slave Hires, 1840-1860. (Box 2, Folder 29, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Receipt issued to Gabriel Wren by Eleanor Cooksey for the hire of Dick (1840).
    Promissory note of Gabriel Wren to James Millan to hire Ann Cornelia (1841).
    Promissory note of August and Samuel Wrenn to Margaret Brook, to hire William (1860).
  - Fairfax County Indentures, 1766-1812. (Box 2, Folder 30, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Agreement between Robert Adam and Henry Gregory (1766).
    Agreement between Anderson Geisling and Kitzmiller (1812).
  - Fairfax County Justice of the Peace Records, 1773-1850. (Box 2, Folder 31, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Demsey Carroll account vs. runaway Eleanor Coleman (1773).
    Appointment of William P. Hutchison to patrol area slave quarters (1850).
    Debt of Alexander Turley (1867).
  - Fairfax County Land Records, 1891-1916. (Box 2, Folder 32, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Plat of Old Court House tract (1843).
    Abstract of title for Sherwood tract (1891).
    Abstract of title for the land of John D. Avil (1895).
    Abstract of title for the land of Edgar E. Clark (1916).
  - Fairfax County Overseers of the Poor, 1798. (Box 2, Folder 33, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    List of votes taken at Frying Pan (now Floris) for Overseers of the Poor for the 2nd District.
  - Fairfax County Plats and Surveys, 1834-1893. (Box 2, Folder 34, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Plat and survey of land of George W. Turley (1834).
    Plat of Hatches purchase of Galpin.
    Courses for deed from L. W. Ball (1846).
    Report of a survey of the Bittinger tract, Shadeland (1893).
  - Fairfax County Reconstruction, 1865-1867. (Box 2, Folder 35, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    List of property of James Wrenn seized by U. S. Troops (1865).
    Receipts of Robert Wrenn for the hire of Mary Blackburn's son (1868). Includes receipts from Bureau Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands.
    Loyalty oath of Alexander Haight and appointment as Overseer of Poor for the 6th District (1869).
  - Fairfax County Road and Bridge Records, 1830-1887. (Box 2, Folder 36, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Report of Middle Turnpike Company and land of the Wrenn family (1830).
    Appointments of surveyors (1838-1842).
    Overseers Road Book for Road District No. 10 (1873).
  - Fairfax County School Records, 1891. (Box 2, Folder 37, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Petitions and reports for Herdnon School District.
  - Fairfax County Wills, 1745-1889. (Box 2, Folder 38, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Will of Richard Brown (1745).
    Will of Charles Thrift (1788).
    Will of Samuel Adams (1791).
    Will of Joseph Lay (1809).
    Will of Nicholas Darne (1831).
    Will of James Wrenn (1843).
    Will of Gabriel Adams (1844).
    Will of John Giley (1869).
    Will of Edmund C. Billinger (1889).
  - Fairfax County Bonds, 1859. (Box 2, Folder 39, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Bond of Samuel J. Tebbs and C.B. Tebbs.
  - Fauquier County County Court, 1794. (Box 2, Folder 40, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    James Cleveland vs. Francis Berryman.
  - Fauquier County Recorded deeds, 1803-1824. (Box 2, Folder 41, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between Nathaniel Greaves and Stephen French (1803).
    Deed between John Scott and William Pickett (1808).
    Deed between L. H. Fitzhugh and Richard Foote (1824).
  - Fauquier County Unrecorded Deeds Grantor F, 1787-1802. (Box 2, Folder 42, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between George W. Fairfax and Moses Roley Knight (1787).
    Deed between Daniel Flowerree and Stephen Bowen (1802).
  - Fauquier County Unrecorded Deeds Grantor H, 1778. (Box 2, Folder 43, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between George Heale and Ambrose Legg.
  - Fauquier County Unrecorded Deeds Grantor S, 1799. (Box 2, Folder 44, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between John Smith and John P. Smith.
  - Fauquier County Unrecorded Deeds Grantor W, 1829. (Box 2, Folder 45, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Deed between Richard Weadon and children.
  - Fairfax County Free Negro and Slave Records, 1803. (Box 2, Folder 46, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1225)
    Manumission of the slaves of Benjamin and Sarah Hitt.
  - Frederick County County Court, 1809. (Box 3, Folder 1, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1226)
    Frederick Lindenbergers assignee vs. William Page.
  - Frederick County Superior Court of Law and Chancery, 1831. (Box 3, Folder 2, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1226)
    Advertisement for Grayham vs. John Hutchinson.
  - Frederick County Fiduciary Records, 1807. (Box 3, Folder 3, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1226)
    Power of attorney of John Piggott.
  - King and Queen County Agreements, 1871. (Box 3, Folder 4, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1226)
    Agreement between Temple Walker and Joseph T. Henley.
  - King and Queen County Recorded Deeds, 1814-1822. (Box 3, Folder 5, Reel Miscellaneous Reel 1226)